There are several methods for determining if your brand is successful.
衡量一个品牌是否成功有几种方法
The one I find to be most approachable is called The Brand Asset Valuator model.
我认为最可行的一个叫做 品牌资产标量模型（Brand Asset Valuator）
The marketing communications agency Young &amp; Rubicam
市场营销公司 Young &amp; Rubicam 在上世纪 90 年代中提出这个模型
developed this model in the mid 90s and it's still relevant today.
至今仍然适用
The idea is, that your company's brand health and future can be evaluated by
模型的核心思想是：可以从四个关键维度收集客户反馈
collecting consumer insight in four key areas: differentiation,
并以此衡量品牌的健康度与成长潜力：差异度、
relevance, esteem, and knowledge.
相关度、美誉度、认知度
Typically, you'll capture these insights through
通常可以采用调查或者采访的方式来
the form of surveys or customer interviews.
收集反馈
In fact, if you do a Google search for a survey monkey BAV,
事实上 如果你 Google “survey monkey BAV"
you'll find already built surveys that you can use to immediately conduct this research.
你会找到很多已设计好的问卷 可以拿来直接用于你的研究
Let's explore these four key areas in more depth.
我们来详细讲解这四个维度
With differentiation, you'll measure by asking
对于差异度 你需要问这些问题：
questions about how often consumers have encountered your brand,
客户“遇到”你的品牌的频率是多少？
if they recognize it,
他们是否认得你的品牌
and what makes it different from your competition.
以及他们是否认为你的品牌与其他品牌不一样
With relevance, it's important to measure whether or
对于相关度 主要是要知道
not a consumer would purchase your product or service.
客户是否会购买你的产品或服务
Does it fit their perceptions on price,
它是否符合他们的心理预期价位
convenience, and how it fits into their lifestyle?
是否为他们提供便利 以及它是否与他们的生活方式匹配？
You can ask simple questions,
你可以设计简单问题 比如
such as the likelihood that they would buy from you,
他们购买产品的可能性
or whether they've purchased what you're selling in the past.
或者 他们是否购买过你的产品
As we get into esteem, it can get a little fuzzier.
美誉度有一点不好理解
Here you're capturing what a consumer feels.
美誉度与客户对你的品牌的“感觉”相关
You'll ask questions about your brand, reputation, and personality.
你可能会问关于品牌的信誉度问题以及品牌个性
How different are you? How reliable,
是否独树一帜？是否可靠、友好、名声好？
Finally, we have knowledge.
最后 认知度
This is where you assess what a consumer knows about your brand.
这里你要测量客户对你的品牌的了解程度
Can they name your product and services?
他们是否能举出几个产品或者服务例子？
Do they know who your competition is?
他们是否知道你的竞争者都是谁？
What did they think your product or service does?
他们是否了解你的产品或服务是干什么的？
The less they know,
他们知道的越少
the lower your brand equity.
你的品牌资产就越低
According to the BAV model,
根据 BAV 模型
you'll then measure how these areas relate to one another.
我们还需要衡量这四个维度之间是如何相关的
You'll find that certain areas are higher than others.
你可能会发现某个维度得分比其他维度高
When differentiation outranks relevance,
比如 当差异度好于相关度
then there's a natural curiosity present in the mind of your consumer.
那么就说明你的客户会自然而然地对你的品牌产生好奇
They want to learn more,
他们希望了解更多情况
but you need a way to determine if your relevant.
但是你需要找到一个方式来确定你的产品或服务是否相关（符合他们的需求）
If the opposite is true,
如果是相反的情况
relevance is higher than differentiation,
即 相关度好于差异度
then you are being grouped together with your competitor.
那么说明对于客户来说 你和其他竞争对手是差不多的
It's likely that consumers aren't seeing a perceived benefit.
他们并没有觉得购买你的产品有任何好处
Instead, they're making a purchase based on convenience.
相反 他们只是根据哪个产品更方便 就购买哪个
When we look at the remaining areas,
再看看其他两个维度
you may find that your esteem is higher than knowledge.
如果你发现美誉度好于认知度
Here, your customers desire of your brand is that they want to purchase
那么说明你的客户渴望购买你的品牌
because they see this esteem and loyalty and they want to experience it firsthand.
因为他们认可你的品牌信誉度 他们想体验一把
If knowledge is higher than esteem,
如果认知度好于美誉度
then customers don't feel like they need to learn anything more about you.
那么说明客户觉得对你的品牌了解的够多了
There's no longer any suspense or interests
你的品牌不再对他们有任何兴趣或吸引力
generated by your brand and their judgment has been made.
他们已经形成了对你的产品的既定印象
You can generally identify how your brand ranks in
简单设计几个关键问题 然后自己研究数据
these various areas by simply asking key questions and reviewing the data on your own.
就可以知道你的品牌在这四个维度上的表现
You'll notice patterns and should be able to pinpoint
你应该可以发现一些总体趋势 然后判断出
what areas of your equity measurement outperform others.
哪些维度表现好 哪些表现不好
Explore the ways to measure your brand equity.
使用不同方法来测量品牌资产
This is meaningful even for a small company,
非常有意义 对于小公司 也是如此
and it can be handled even outside of
形式也不仅限于调查
a survey by simply having a conversation with your customers.
简单地与客户交谈也是可以的